The	B-ORG
Australian	I-ORG
Banana	I-ORG
Growers	I-ORG
'	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
(	O
ABGC	B-ORG
)	O
says	O
the	O
successful	O
eradication	O
of	O
banana	B-DISEASE
freckle	I-DISEASE
in	O
the	O
Northern	B-LOC
Territory	I-LOC
is	O
a	O
clear	O
signal	O
to	O
markets	O
not	O
just	O
locally	O
,	O

but	O
around	O
the	O
world	O
that	O
the	O
Northern	B-LOC
Territory	I-LOC
,	O
and	O
Australia	B-GPE
as	O
a	O
whole	O
,	O
is	O
free	O
of	O
the	O
disease	O
.	O

 	O
Banana	B-DISEASE
freckle	I-DISEASE
was	O
detected	O
in	O
Cavendish	B-CROP
bananas	I-CROP
in	O
NT	B-LOC
in	O
2013	B-DATE
.	O
Today	B-DATE
there	O
was	O
a	O
formal	O
declaration	O
that	O
Banana	B-DISEASE
Freckle	I-DISEASE
(	O
Phyllosticta	B-PATHOGEN
cavendishii	I-PATHOGEN
)	O
has	O
been	O
officially	O
eradicated	O
from	O
Australia	B-GPE
following	O
the	O
successful	O
completion	O
of	O
the	O
National	O
Banana	O
Freckle	O
Eradication	O
Program	O
Response	O
.	O

 	O
"	O
The	O
eradication	O
process	O
was	O
completed	O
in	O
four	O
phases	O
over	O
a	B-DATE
5	I-DATE
year	I-DATE
period	O
,	O
"	O
ABGC	B-PATHOGEN
Chair	O
Stephen	O
Lowe	O
said	O
.	O
"	O
In	O
the	O
first	O
,	O
all	O
banana	B-CROP
plants	O
found	O
in	O
six	O
red	O
zones	O
were	O
destroyed	O
and	O
movement	O
of	O
banana	B-CROP
plants	O
was	O
restricted	O
.	O

This	O
was	O
followed	O
by	O
a	O
'	O
host	O
-	O
free	O
'	O
period	O
,	O
for	O
6	B-DATE
months	I-DATE
including	O
one	O
wet	O
season	O
where	O
it	O
was	O
prohibited	O
to	O
grow	O
any	O
bananas	B-CROP
.	O
Phase	O
3	O
involved	O
a	O
controlled	O
replanting	O
of	O
disease	O
free	O
sentinel	O
banana	B-CROP
plants	O
which	O
were	O
monitored	O
for	O
banana	B-DISEASE
freckle	I-DISEASE
.	O

During	O
this	O
time	O
,	O
people	O
were	O
permitted	O
to	O
buy	O
banana	B-CROP
plants	O
again	O
,	O
but	O
only	O
from	O
authorised	O
outlets	O
and	O
with	O
a	O
permit	O
.	O
The	O
final	O
phase	O
involved	O
systematic	O
surveillance	O
and	O
monitoring	O
banana	B-CROP
plants	O
to	O
prove	O
the	O
NT	B-LOC
's	O
freedom	O
of	O
banana	B-DISEASE
Freckle	I-DISEASE
.	O

It	O
's	O
a	O
real	O
testament	O
to	O
everyone	O
involved	O
that	O
such	O
a	O
large	O
eradication	O
process	O
has	O
been	O
so	O
successful	O
.	O
"	O
 	O
The	O
Freckle	O
Response	O
has	O
been	O
the	O
largest	O
Emergency	O
Plant	O
Pest	O
Response	O
under	O
the	O
Plant	O
Health	O
Deed	O
ever	O
undertaken	O
in	O
Australia	B-GPE
.	O

Mr	O
Lowe	O
added	O
that	O
the	O
impact	O
of	O
banana	B-DISEASE
freckle	I-DISEASE
spreading	O
further	O
afield	O
could	O
have	O
greatly	O
impacted	O
the	O
industry	O
,	O
particularly	O
if	O
it	O
reached	O
the	O
major	O
growing	O
area	O
in	O
Far	B-LOC
North	I-LOC
Queensland	I-LOC
.	O

 	O
"	O
The	O
disease	O
could	O
have	O
significantly	O
reduced	O
production	O
,	O
affecting	O
our	O
growers	O
'	O
ability	O
to	O
supply	O
local	O
fruit	B-PLANT_PART
to	O
Australian	B-GPE
consumers	O
,	O
"	O
he	O
said	O
.	O
"	O
On	O
top	O
of	O
this	O
,	O

it	O
would	O
have	O
affected	O
our	O
good	O
standing	O
internationally	O
and	O
export	O
market	O
opportunities	O
.	O
"	O

 	O
Although	O
the	O
Northern	B-LOC
Territory	I-LOC
growers	O
have	O
been	O
supplying	O
their	O
local	O
markets	O
again	O
for	O
at	B-DATE
least	I-DATE
12	I-DATE
months	I-DATE
,	O
there	O
have	O
also	O
been	O
restrictions	O
on	O
exporting	O
plant	O
material	O
from	O
the	O
Territory	O
,	O

which	O
will	O
now	O
be	O
revisited	O
.	O

Mr	O
Lowe	O
says	O
this	O
official	O
declaration	O
is	O
just	O
one	O
example	O
of	O
how	O
industry	O
and	O
government	O
can	O
come	O
together	O
to	O
maintain	O
that	O
famed	O
'	O
clean	O
,	O
green	O
'	O
image	O
for	O
future	O
generations	O
.	O

 	O
"	O
Australian	B-GPE
banana	B-CROP
growers	O
are	O
committed	O
to	O
maintaining	O
good	O
biosecurity	O
,	O
not	O
only	O
to	O
protect	O
their	O
own	O
farms	O
,	O
but	O
their	O
industry	O
as	O
a	O
whole	O
,	O
"	O
he	O
said	O
.	O

"	O

There	O
are	O
currently	O
rigorous	O
systems	O
in	O
place	O
designed	O
to	O
ensure	O
a	O
constant	O
supply	O
of	O
healthy	O
,	O
locally	O
grown	O
bananas	B-CROP
to	O
Australian	B-GPE
consumers	O
.	O
Australian	B-GPE
banana	B-CROP
biosecurity	O
is	O
regarded	O
as	O
among	O
the	O
best	O
in	O
the	O
world	O
and	O
something	O
all	O
stakeholders	O
take	O
very	O
seriously	O
.	O

Aussie	O
consumers	O
love	O
their	O
Aussie	O
bananas	B-CROP
-	O
and	O
we	O
love	O
being	O
able	O
to	O
grow	O
them	O
.	O
"	O
 	O
Banana	B-CROP
growers	O
across	O
the	O
country	O
funded	O
half	O
of	O
the	O
costs	O
of	O
the	O
National	O
Banana	O
Freckle	O
Eradication	O
Response	O
Program	O
through	O
a	O
levy	O
,	O

and	O
also	O
contributed	O
technical	O
expertise	O
and	O
knowledge	O
.	O

 	O
"	O
The	O
Territory	O
's	O
commercial	O
growers	O
and	O
backyard	O
banana	B-CROP
lovers	O
have	O
no	O
doubt	O
felt	O
the	O
brunt	O
of	O
this	O
effort	O
,	O
Mr	O
Lowe	O
said	O
.	O
"	O
We	O
know	O
it	O
's	O
not	O
easy	O
to	O
lose	O
banana	O
plants	O
in	O
any	O
circumstance	O
–	O
be	O
it	O
natural	O
disaster	O
,	O

disease	O
or	O
otherwise	O
.	O

We	O
thank	O
them	O
for	O
their	O
part	O
in	O
ensuring	O
our	O
vibrant	O
Australian	B-GPE
industry	O
is	O
free	O
from	O
this	O
potentially	O
devastating	O
disease	O
.	O
We	O
also	O
appreciate	O
the	O
dedication	O
of	O
the	O
Northern	B-ORG
Territory	I-ORG
Department	I-ORG
of	I-ORG
Primary	I-ORG
Industries	I-ORG
for	O
running	O
the	O
Eradication	O
Program	O
and	O
the	O
countless	O
hours	O
put	O
in	O
by	O
the	O
various	O
government	O
and	O
industry	O
representatives	O
who	O
contributed	O
.	O

Of	O
course	O
,	O
commercial	O
growers	O
of	O
all	O
sizes	O
across	O
Australia	B-GPE
have	O
also	O
contributed	O
$	O
12	O
million	O
to	O
this	O
effort	O
.	O
The	O
ABGC	B-ORG
acknowledges	O
that	O
this	O
is	O
no	O
small	O
undertaking	O
on	O
their	O
behalf	O
and	O
thanks	O
them	O
for	O
their	O
unwavering	O
commitment	O
to	O
their	O
industry	O
.	O

"	O

 	O
For	O
more	O
information	O
 	O
Stephen	O
Lowe	O
 	O
Australian	B-ORG
Banana	I-ORG
Growers	I-ORG
'	I-ORG
Council	I-ORG
 	O
Phone	O
:	O
+61	O
7	O
3278	O
4786	O
 	O
info@abgc.org.au	O
 	O
www.abgc.org.au	O

A	O
new	O
species	O
,	O
Trichocladium	B-PATHOGEN
solani	I-PATHOGEN
,	O
was	O
isolated	O
from	O
potato	B-CROP
(	O
Solanum	B-CROP
tuberosum	I-CROP
L.	O
)	O
tubers	B-PLANT_PART
from	O
Russia	B-GPE
.	O
The	O
species	O
has	O
no	O
observed	O
teleomorph	O
and	O
is	O
characterized	O
morphologically	O
by	O
non	O
-	O
specific	O
Acremonium	O
-	O
like	O
conidia	O
on	O
single	O
phialides	O
and	O
chains	O
of	O
swollen	O
chlamydospores	O
.	O

Phylogenetic	O
analysis	O
placed	O
the	O
new	O
species	O
in	O
a	O
monophyletic	O
clade	O
inside	O
the	O
Trichocladium	O
lineage	O
with	O
a	O
high	O
level	O
of	O
support	O
from	O
a	O
multi	O
-	O
locus	O
analysis	O
of	O
three	O
gene	O
regions	O
:	O
ITS	O
,	O

tub2	O
,	O
and	O
rpb2	O
.	O

ITS	O
is	O
found	O
to	O
be	O
insufficient	O
for	O
species	O
delimitation	O
and	O
is	O
not	O
recommended	O
for	O
identification	O
purposes	O
in	O
screening	O
studies	O
.	O
T.	B-PATHOGEN
solani	I-PATHOGEN
is	O
pathogenic	O
to	O
potato	B-CROP
tubers	B-PLANT_PART
and	O
causes	O
lesions	B-SYMPTOM
that	O
look	O
similar	O
to	O
symptoms	O
of	O
Fusarium	B-DISEASE
dry	I-DISEASE
rot	I-DISEASE
infection	O
but	O
with	O
yellowish	B-SYMPTOM
or	I-SYMPTOM
greenish	I-SYMPTOM
tint	I-SYMPTOM
in	I-SYMPTOM
the	I-SYMPTOM
necrotized	I-SYMPTOM
area	O
.	O

The	O
disease	O
has	O
been	O
named	O
"	O
yellow	B-DISEASE
rot	I-DISEASE
of	I-DISEASE
potato	I-DISEASE
tubers	I-DISEASE
"	O
.	O

The	O
objective	O
of	O
this	O
study	O
was	O
to	O
identify	O
the	O
causal	O
agent	O
of	O
anthracnose	B-DISEASE
disease	I-DISEASE
of	O
cassava	B-CROP
in	O
Thailand	B-GPE
.	O
The	O
study	O
was	O
carried	O
out	O
by	O
collecting	O
cassava	B-CROP
samples	O
with	O
anthracnose	B-DISEASE
symptoms	O
from	O
various	O
planting	O
areas	O
including	O
10	O
districts	O
of	O
eight	O
provinces	O
in	O
Thailand	B-GPE
.	O

One	O
hundred	O
and	O
thirty‐six	O
Colletotrichum	O
samples	O
were	O
isolated	O
from	O
cassava	B-DISEASE
anthracnose	I-DISEASE
lesions	B-SYMPTOM
on	I-SYMPTOM
leaves	I-SYMPTOM
,	I-SYMPTOM
petioles	I-SYMPTOM
and	I-SYMPTOM
stems	I-SYMPTOM
.	O
Thirty‐eight	O
single‐spore	O
isolates	O
were	O
subsequently	O
obtained	O
and	O
cultured	O
on	O
half	O
potato	O
dextrose	O
agar	O
for	O
morphological	O
and	O
molecular	O
characterizations	O
.	O

All	O
38	O
isolates	O
were	O
pathogenic	O
with	O
varying	O
degrees	O
of	O
virulence	O
when	O
tested	O
on	O
detached	O
leaves	B-PLANT_PART
of	O
Kasetsart	O
50	O
,	O
a	O
susceptible	O
cassava	B-CROP
cultivar	O
.	O
Based	O
on	O
their	O
growth	O
habit	O
,	O

colony	O
morphology	O
,	O
conidial	O
morphology	O
and	O
the	O
internal	O
transcribed	O
spacer	O
sequences	O
similarity	O
to	O
that	O
of	O
Colletotrichum	B-PATHOGEN
accessions	O
in	O
the	O
GenBank	B-ORG
,	O
one	O
isolate	O
was	O
identified	O
as	O
C.	B-PATHOGEN
 	I-PATHOGEN
capsici	I-PATHOGEN
,	O

one	O
as	O
C.	B-PATHOGEN
 	I-PATHOGEN
lindemuthianum	I-PATHOGEN
,	O
two	O
as	O
C.	B-PATHOGEN
 	I-PATHOGEN
aeschynomene	I-PATHOGEN
,	O
four	O
as	O
C.	B-PATHOGEN
 	I-PATHOGEN
boninense	I-PATHOGEN
and	O
28	O
C.	B-PATHOGEN
 	I-PATHOGEN
gloeosporioides	I-PATHOGEN
species	I-PATHOGEN
complex	I-PATHOGEN
.	O

Geographically	O
,	O
the	O
cosmopolitan	O
C.	B-PATHOGEN
 	I-PATHOGEN
gloeosporioides	I-PATHOGEN
species	I-PATHOGEN
complex	I-PATHOGEN
was	O
found	O
in	O
all	O
regions	O
,	O
but	O
other	O
species	O
were	O
found	O
only	O
in	O
particular	O
regions	O
.	O
This	O
is	O
,	O
so	O
far	O
,	O

the	O
first	O
report	O
of	O
Colletotrichum	B-PATHOGEN
complex	I-PATHOGEN
species	I-PATHOGEN
associated	O
with	O
cassava	B-DISEASE
anthracnose	I-DISEASE
in	O
Thailand	B-GPE
.	O

Tel	O
:	O
+221	O
77691	O
6072	O
 	O
Email	O
:	O
titancons96@gmail.com	O

Early	B-DISEASE
blight	I-DISEASE
of	O
potato	B-DISEASE
(	O
Solanum	B-CROP
tuberosum	I-CROP
)	O
is	O
caused	O
by	O
Alternaria	B-PATHOGEN
species	I-PATHOGEN
and	O
occurs	O
annually	O
in	O
major	O
potato	B-CROP
producing	O
regions	O
of	O
Russia	B-GPE
.	O
Diseased	O
potato	B-CROP
leaves	B-PLANT_PART
displaying	O
early	B-DISEASE
blight	I-DISEASE
symptoms	O
were	O
collected	O
in	O
July	B-DATE
2016	I-DATE
from	O
a	O
commercial	O
field	O
in	O
Primorsky	B-GPE
Krai	I-GPE
,	O

Russia	B-GPE
(	O
43.8242	B-LOC
°	I-LOC
N	I-LOC
,	I-LOC
131.6219	I-LOC
°	I-LOC
E	I-LOC
)	O
.	O

The	O
disease	O
incidence	O
was	O
30	O
to	O
40	O
%	O
.	O
The	O
initial	O
symptoms	O
appeared	O
as	O
typical	O
early	B-DISEASE
blight	I-DISEASE
symptoms	O
with	O
a	O
dark	B-SYMPTOM
brown	I-SYMPTOM
margin	I-SYMPTOM
and	I-SYMPTOM
diffused	I-SYMPTOM
chlorosis	I-SYMPTOM
on	I-SYMPTOM
the	I-SYMPTOM
leaf	I-SYMPTOM
blade	I-SYMPTOM
.	O

Symptomatic	O
leaves	B-PLANT_PART
from	O
different	O
plants	O
were	O
randomly	O
collected	O
to	O
isolate	O
axenic	O
cultures	O
of	O
the	O
causal	O
agents	O
.	O
Infected	O
leaves	B-PLANT_PART
were	O
placed	O
in	O
wet	O
chambers	O
(	O
moist	O
filter	O
papers	O
in	O
Petri	O
dishes	O
)	O
,	O

Crous	O
et	O
al	O
.	O

2009	B-DATE
)	O
in	O
Petri	O
dishes	O
and	O
incubated	O
at	O
25	O
°	O
C	O
for	O
7	B-DATE
d	I-DATE
in	O
the	O
dark	O
.	O
Colonies	O
were	O
white	O
-	O
olivaceous	O
,	O
reverse	O
side	O
-	O
olivaceous	O
.	O
Isolates	O
were	O
transferred	O
onto	O
potato	O
carrot	O
agar	O
(	O
PCA	O
,	O

Crous	O
et	O
al	O
.	O

2009	B-DATE
)	O
and	O
incubated	O
at	O
22	O
°	O
C	O
under	O
a	O
16	B-DATE
h/8	I-DATE
h	I-DATE
dark	O
/	O
light	O
photoperiod	O
for	O
7	B-DATE
d	I-DATE
to	O
stimulate	O
sporulation	O
.	O
Most	O
isolates	O
(	O
85	O
%	O
)	O
were	O
identified	O
as	O
A.	B-PATHOGEN
protenta	I-PATHOGEN
according	O
to	O
the	O
morphological	O
characteristics	O
and	O
molecular	O
data	O
,	O

although	O
one	O
isolate	O
showed	O
sporulation	O
that	O
was	O
somewhat	O
atypical	O
,	O
having	O
a	O
smaller	O
(	O
especially	O
narrower	O
or	O
more	O
slender	O
)	O
conidia	O
.	O

Conidiophores	O
were	O
long	O
,	O
erect	O
,	O
and	O
65	O
to	O
100	O
μm	O
×	O
5	O
to	O
6	O
μm	O
in	O
size	O
.	O
Conidia	O
were	O
solitary	O
,	O
long	O
-	O
ovoid	O
in	O
body	O
with	O
six	O
to	O
eight	O
transverse	O
septa	O
,	O

and	O
85	O
to	O
100	O
μm×	O
6	O
to	O
10	O
μm	O
in	O
size	O
.	O

Conidial	O
beaks	O
were	O
filamentous	O
,	O
110	O
to	O
200	O
μm	O
×	O
2	O
to	O
5	O
μm	O
in	O
size	O
.	O
Genomic	O
DNA	O
was	O
extracted	O
from	O
cultured	O
isolates	O
using	O
the	O
CTAB	O
-	O
chloroform	O
extraction	O
method	O
(	O
Griffith	O
&	O
Shaw	O
1998	B-DATE
)	O
,	O

and	O
five	O
gene	O
regions	O
including	O
the	O
internal	O
transcribed	O
spacer	O
(	O
ITS	O
)	O
region	O
,	O
translation	O
elongation	O
factor	O
1	O
-	O
alpha	O
(	O
tef1	O
)	O
,	O
RNA	O
polymerase	O
second	O
largest	O
subunit	O
(	O
rpb2	O
)	O
,	O

Alternaria	B-PATHOGEN
major	I-PATHOGEN
allergen	O
(	O
Alt	O
a	O
1	O
)	O
and	O
glyceraldehyde-3	O
-	O
phosphate	O
dehydrogenase	O
(	O
GAPDH	O
)	O
genes	O
were	O
amplified	O
with	O
the	O
primer	O
pairs	O
ITS1	O
/	O
ITS4	O
,	O
EF1	O
-	O
728F	O
/	O
EF1	O
-	O
986R	O
,	O

RPB2	O
-	O
5F2	O
/	O
FRPB2	O
-	O
7cR	O
,	O
Alt	O
-	O
for	O
/	O
Alt	O
-	O
rev	O
,	O
and	O
gpd1	O
/	O
gpd2	O
respectively	O
(	O
Woudenberg	O
et	O
al	O
.	O

2014	B-DATE
)	O
.	O
PCR	O
products	O
were	O
Sanger	O
sequenced	O
.	O
All	O
sequences	O
for	O
isolate	O
A16PrPL21	B-PATHOGEN
were	O
identical	O
to	O
isolate	O
CBS	O
105.51	O
;	O
(	O
accession	O
nos	O
.	O
:	O
ITS	O
,	O
KJ718105	O
;	O
tef1	O
,	O

KJ718454	O
;	O
rpb2	O
,	O
KJ718279	O
;	O
Alt	O
a	O
1	O
,	O
KJ718625	O
;	O
gpd	O
KJ717959	O
)	O
of	O
A.	B-PATHOGEN
alternariacida	I-PATHOGEN
Woudenb	O
.	O
&	O

Crous	O
.	O
ITS	O
,	O
tef1	O
,	O
rpb2	O
,	O
Alt	O
a	O
1	O
and	O
gpd	O
sequences	O
were	O
deposited	O
in	O
GenBank	B-ORG
under	O
the	O
accessions	O
OM348531	O
,	O
MN580518	O
,	O
MN580529	O
,	O
MN562258	O
and	O
MN544404	O
respectively	O
.	O

Based	O
on	O
morphological	O
and	O
molecular	O
data	O
,	O
the	O
isolate	O
was	O
identified	O
as	O
Alternaria	B-PATHOGEN
alternariacida	I-PATHOGEN
Woudenb	O
.	O
&	O
Crous	O
.	O
A.	B-PATHOGEN
alternariacida	I-PATHOGEN
is	O
closely	O
related	O
to	O
A.	B-PATHOGEN
silybi	I-PATHOGEN
,	O
which	O
is	O
also	O
found	O
in	O
the	O
Far	B-LOC
East	I-LOC
(	O
Woudenberg	O
et	O
al	O
.	O

2014	B-DATE
)	O
.	O
Phylogenetic	O
distances	O
between	O
these	O
strains	O
are	O
based	O
on	O
differences	O
at	O
the	O
ITS	O
,	O
TEF1	O
and	O
Alt	O
a	O
1	O
gene	O
regions	O
.	O
A	O
pathogenicity	O
test	O
was	O
carried	O
out	O
with	O
isolate	O
A16PrPL21	O
on	O
nine	O
5	B-DATE
-	I-DATE
week	I-DATE
-	I-DATE
old	I-DATE
healthy	O
potato	B-CROP
plants	O
(	O
cv	O
.	O

Nevsky	O
)	O
grown	O
in	O
a	O
greenhouse	O
at	O
23	O
±	O
2	O
°	O
C	O
.	O
Seed	B-PLANT_PART
tubers	B-PLANT_PART
were	O
grown	O
in	O
the	O
greenhouse	O
to	O
obtain	O
the	O
seedlings	O
.	O
Inoculation	O
was	O
performed	O
by	O
spraying	O
a	O
conidial	O
suspension	O
(	O
105	O
spores	O
/	O
ml	O
)	O
prepared	O
from	O
10	B-DATE
-	I-DATE
day	I-DATE
-	I-DATE
old	I-DATE
A.	B-PATHOGEN
alternariacida	I-PATHOGEN
culture	O
grown	O
on	O
PCA	O
at	O
23	O
°	O
C	O
with	O
a	O
12	B-DATE
-	I-DATE
h	I-DATE
photoperiod	O
.	O

Nine	O
negative	O
control	O
plants	O
were	O
treated	O
with	O
sterile	O
distilled	O
water	O
.	O
The	O
inoculated	O
plants	O
were	O
then	O
maintained	O
in	O
a	O
greenhouse	O
at	O
25	O
°	O
C	O
with	O
high	O
humidity	O
and	O
12	B-DATE
-	I-DATE
h	I-DATE
light	O
period	O
.	O

All	O
test	O
plants	O
were	O
covered	O
with	O
plastic	O
bags	O
for	O
24	B-DATE
h	I-DATE
to	O
maintain	O
high	O
relative	O
humidity	O
and	O
incubated	O
at	O
24	O
to	O
28	O
°	O
C	O
.	O
Leaf	B-DISEASE
spot	I-DISEASE
symptoms	O
,	O
brown	B-SYMPTOM
lesions	I-SYMPTOM
with	I-SYMPTOM
chlorotic	I-SYMPTOM
halos	I-SYMPTOM
,	O

similar	O
to	O
those	O
previously	O
observed	O
in	O
naturally	O
infected	O
plants	O
,	O
appeared	O
5	B-DATE
d	I-DATE
post	I-DATE
inoculation	O
for	O
all	O
inoculated	O
plants	O
.	O

After	O
7	B-DATE
d	I-DATE
,	O
the	O
spots	O
reached	O
18	O
to	O
25	O
mm	O
in	O
size	O
.	O
The	O
symptoms	O
were	O
similar	O
to	O
the	O
original	O
symptoms	O
that	O
occurred	O
in	O
the	O
field	O
.	O
Negative	O
control	O
leaves	B-PLANT_PART
were	O
symptomless	O
.	O

Koch	O
's	O
postulates	O
were	O
fulfilled	O
by	O
reisolating	O
the	O
pathogen	O
from	O
inoculated	O
leaves	B-PLANT_PART
and	O
identified	O
as	O
A.	B-PATHOGEN
alternaricida	I-PATHOGEN
by	O
rpb2	O
gene	O
sequence	O
and	O
morphological	O
characteristics	O
.	O
To	O
our	O
knowledge	O
,	O
this	O
is	O
the	O
first	O
report	O
of	O
disease	O
caused	O
by	O
A.	B-PATHOGEN
alternaricida	I-PATHOGEN
on	O
potato	B-CROP
plants	O
.	O

Early	B-DISEASE
blight	I-DISEASE
,	O
caused	O
by	O
large	O
-	O
spored	O
Alternaria	B-PATHOGEN
,	O
is	O
a	O
widespread	O
disease	O
on	O
potato	B-CROP
.	O
A.	B-CROP
alternaricida	I-CROP
is	O
among	O
a	O
group	O
of	O
species	O
that	O
cause	O
early	B-DISEASE
blight	I-DISEASE
,	O

according	O
to	O
current	O
research	O
.	O

Studies	O
of	O
the	O
Alternaria	B-PATHOGEN
species	I-PATHOGEN
'	O
biology	O
and	O
analyses	O
of	O
their	O
distribution	O
are	O
important	O
for	O
improving	O
potato	B-CROP
protection	O
from	O
early	B-DISEASE
blight	I-DISEASE
.	O

We	O
set	O
out	O
to	O
characterize	O
the	O
CBSV	B-PATHOGEN
and	O
UCBSV	B-PATHOGEN
whole	O
genomes	O
from	O
the	O
26	O
previously	O
published	O
genomes	O
and	O
three	O
new	O
from	O
Uganda	B-GPE
,	O
using	O
NGS	O
data	O
with	O
the	O
goal	O
of	O
uncovering	O
genetic	O
patterns	O
that	O
explain	O
the	O
observed	O
biological	O
differences	O
.	O

In	O
this	O
paper	O
,	O
we	O
report	O
phylogenetic	O
relationships	O
,	O
rates	O
of	O
synonymous	O
and	O
non	O
-	O
synonymous	O
substitutions	O
,	O
and	O
whole	O
genome	O
-	O
based	O
evolutionary	O
rates	O
for	O
CBSV	B-PATHOGEN
and	O
UCBSV	B-PATHOGEN
.	O

Using	O
the	O
whole	O
genome	O
sequences	O
we	O
produced	O
the	O
first	O
coalescent	O
based	O
species	O
tree	O
estimation	O
for	O
CBSV	B-PATHOGEN
and	O
UCBSV	B-PATHOGEN
which	O
supports	O
previously	O
published	O
studies	O
pointing	O
to	O
multiple	O
species	O
of	O
both	O
CBSV	B-PATHOGEN
and	O
UCBSV	B-PATHOGEN
.	O

This	O
new	O
species	O
framework	O
led	O
to	O
the	O
finding	O
that	O
CBSV	B-PATHOGEN
has	O
a	O
faster	O
rate	O
of	O
evolution	O
when	O
compared	O
with	O
UCBSV	B-PATHOGEN
.	O
The	O
genes	O
responsible	O
for	O
CBSVs	B-PATHOGEN
rapid	O
rate	O
of	O
evolution	O
are	O
NIa	O
,	O

6K2	O
,	O
NIb	O
and	O
P1	O
.	O

Furthermore	O
,	O
we	O
have	O
discovered	O
that	O
for	O
CBSV	B-PATHOGEN
,	O
rates	O
of	O
nonsynonomous	O
substitutions	O
are	O
more	O
predominant	O
than	O
synonymous	O
substitution	O
and	O
occur	O
across	O
the	O
entire	O
genome	O
.	O
All	O
comparative	O
analyses	O
between	O
CBSV	B-PATHOGEN
and	O
UCBSV	B-PATHOGEN
presented	O
suggests	O
CBSV	B-PATHOGEN
is	O
outsmarting	O
the	O
cassava	B-CROP
immune	O
system	O
,	O

thus	O
is	O
more	O
devastating	O
and	O
harder	O
to	O
control	O
.	O

Highlights	O
Recent	O
advances	O
in	O
the	O
research	O
on	O
cassava	B-CROP
(	O
Manihot	B-CROP
esculenta	I-CROP
)	O
biopolymers	O
and	O
fibers	O
,	O
and	O
their	O
potential	O
industrial	O
applications	O
,	O
were	O
discussed	O
.	O
Properties	O
of	O
starch	O
,	O
fibers	O
,	O

polymers	O
,	O
and	O
composites	O
derived	O
from	O
cassava	B-CROP
were	O
discussed	O
.	O

Efforts	O
to	O
enhance	O
the	O
properties	O
of	O
cassava	B-CROP
composites	O
were	O
brought	O
into	O
focus	O
.	O
Detailed	O
reports	O
on	O
macro	O
and	O
nano	O
-	O
sized	O
cassava	B-CROP
fibers	O
and	O
starch	O
,	O
and	O
their	O
fabrication	O
as	O
blend	O
polymers	O
,	O

biocomposites	O
,	O
and	O
hybrid	O
composites	O
,	O
were	O
reviewed	O
.	O

Abstract	O
The	O
rapid	O
use	O
of	O
petroleum	O
resources	O
coupled	O
with	O
increased	O
awareness	O
of	O
global	O
environmental	O
problems	O
associated	O
with	O
the	O
use	O
of	O
petroleum	O
-	O
based	O
plastics	O
is	O
a	O
major	O
driving	O
force	O
in	O
the	O
acceptance	O
of	O
natural	O
fibers	O
and	O
biopolymers	O
as	O
green	O
materials	O
.	O

Because	O
of	O
their	O
environmentally	O
friendly	O
and	O
sustainable	O
nature	O
,	O
natural	O
fibers	O
and	O
biopolymers	O
have	O
gained	O
significant	O
attention	O
from	O
scientists	O
and	O
industries	O
.	O
Cassava	B-CROP
(	O
Manihot	B-CROP
esculenta	I-CROP
)	O
is	O
a	O
plant	O
that	O
has	O
various	O
purposes	O
for	O
use	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
the	O
primary	O
source	O
of	O
food	O
in	O
many	O
countries	O
and	O
is	O
also	O
used	O
in	O
the	O
production	O
of	O
biocomposites	O
,	O
biopolymers	O
,	O
and	O
biofibers	O
.	O
Starch	O
from	O
cassava	B-CROP
can	O
be	O
plasticized	O
,	O

reinforced	O
with	O
fibers	O
,	O
or	O
blended	O
with	O
other	O
polymers	O
to	O
strengthen	O
their	O
properties	O
.	O

Besides	O
that	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
currently	O
used	O
as	O
a	O
raw	O
material	O
for	O
bioethanol	O
and	O
renewable	O
energy	O
production	O
.	O
This	O
comprehensive	O
review	O
paper	O
explains	O
the	O
latest	O
developments	O
in	O
bioethanol	O
compounds	O
from	O
cassava	B-CROP
and	O
gives	O
a	O
detailed	O
report	O
on	O
macro	O
and	O
nano	O
-	O
sized	O
cassava	B-CROP
fibers	O
and	O
starch	O
,	O

and	O
their	O
fabrication	O
as	O
blend	O
polymers	O
,	O
biocomposites	O
,	O
and	O
hybrid	O
composites	O
.	O

The	O
review	O
also	O
highlights	O
the	O
potential	O
utilization	O
of	O
cassava	B-CROP
fibers	O
and	O
biopolymers	O
for	O
industrial	O
applications	O
such	O
as	O
food	O
,	O
bioenergy	O
,	O
packaging	O
,	O
automotive	O
,	O
and	O
others	O
.	O

China	B-GPE
is	O
the	O
largest	O
producer	O
of	O
bananas	B-CROP
,	O
ranking	O
second	O
in	O
the	O
world	O
after	O
India	B-GPE
.	O
Since	O
2015	B-DATE
,	O
affected	O
by	O
multiple	O
factors	O
such	O
as	O
sluggish	O
market	O
conditions	O
,	O
banana	B-DISEASE
fusarium	I-DISEASE
wilt	I-DISEASE
,	O

and	O
rising	O
planting	O
costs	O
,	O
banana	B-CROP
farmers	O
have	O
seriously	O
abandoned	O
their	O
crops	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
planting	O
areas	O
in	O
major	O
producing	O
areas	O
and	O
provinces	O
have	O
all	O
decreased	O
.	O

 	O
Although	O
the	O
annual	O
output	O
of	O
bananas	B-CROP
in	O
China	B-GPE
is	O
at	O
the	O
level	O
of	O
10	O
million	O
tons	O
,	O
due	O
to	O
the	O
huge	O
banana	B-CROP
consumption	O
market	O
in	O
China	B-GPE
,	O
domestic	O
bananas	B-CROP
can	O
not	O
fully	O
meet	O
the	O
consumption	O
needs	O
of	O
the	O
people	O
.	O

In	O
recent	B-DATE
years	I-DATE
,	O
China	B-GPE
's	O
demand	O
for	O
imported	O
bananas	B-CROP
has	O
continued	O
to	O
rise	O
.	O
 	O
China	B-GPE
has	O
five	O
major	O
sources	O
of	O
banana	B-CROP
imports	O
,	O
namely	O
the	O
Philippines	B-GPE
,	O
Ecuador	B-GPE
,	O

Vietnam	B-GPE
,	O
Myanmar	B-GPE
and	O
Thailand	B-GPE
.	O

Due	O
to	O
the	O
geographical	O
proximity	O
of	O
Southeast	B-LOC
Asian	I-LOC
countries	O
to	O
China	B-GPE
,	O
the	O
quality	O
of	O
bananas	B-CROP
is	O
also	O
good	O
,	O
and	O
most	O
of	O
the	O
bananas	B-CROP
imported	O
by	O
China	B-GPE
come	O
from	O
Southeast	B-LOC
Asia	I-LOC
.	O

 	O
In	O
Europe	B-LOC
,	O
Belgium	B-GPE
is	O
the	O
country	O
with	O
the	O
largest	O
banana	B-CROP
import	O
volume	O
in	O
the	O
EU	B-LOC
.	O
The	O
imported	O
bananas	B-CROP
are	O
mainly	O
from	O
Colombia	B-GPE
,	O
Costa	B-GPE
Rica	I-GPE
,	O
Ecuador	B-GPE
and	O
other	O
American	B-GPE
countries	O
,	O

but	O
the	O
imported	O
bananas	B-CROP
are	O
not	O
all	O
for	O
domestic	O
consumption	O
and	O
are	O
mainly	O
used	O
in	O
the	O
re	O
-	O
export	O
trade	O
.	O

According	O
to	O
the	B-ORG
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Commodity	I-ORG
Trade	I-ORG
Statistics	I-ORG
Database	I-ORG
(	O
UN	B-ORG
Comtrade	I-ORG
)	O
,	O
Belgium	B-GPE
and	O
the	O
Netherlands	B-GPE
,	O
as	O
the	O
major	O
importers	O
of	O
bananas	B-CROP
in	O
the	O
EU	B-LOC
.	O
In	O
2019	B-DATE
,	O

the	O
import	O
volume	O
of	O
bananas	B-CROP
reached	O
1,178,200	O
tons	O
and	O
1,015,900	O
tons	O
respectively	O
.	O

At	O
the	O
same	O
time	O
,	O
the	O
export	O
volume	O
of	O
bananas	B-CROP
in	O
that	B-DATE
year	I-DATE
was	O
947,200	O
tons	O
and	O
814,100	O
tons	O
respectively	O
,	O
and	O
domestic	O
consumption	O
was	O
within	O
200,000	O
tons	O
.	O
 	O

China	B-GPE
is	O
the	O
fastest	O
-	O
growing	O
market	O
for	O
banana	B-CROP
imports	O
 	O
Although	O
both	O
India	B-GPE
and	O
China	B-GPE
are	O
big	O
banana	B-CROP
producers	O
,	O
unlike	O
India	B-GPE
,	O
which	O
hardly	O
imports	O
bananas	B-CROP
,	O
China	B-GPE
still	O
needs	O
to	O
import	O
millions	O
of	O
tons	O
of	O
bananas	B-CROP
every	B-DATE
year	I-DATE
to	O
make	O
up	O
for	O
the	O
market	O
gap	O
.	O

Although	O
China	B-GPE
produces	O
its	O
own	O
bananas	B-CROP
and	O
ranks	O
second	O
in	O
the	O
world	O
in	O
terms	O
of	O
output	O
,	O
reaching	O
more	O
than	O
10	O
million	O
tons	O
,	O
it	O
still	O
needs	O
to	O
import	O
a	O
large	O
number	O
of	O
bananas	B-CROP
every	B-DATE
year	I-DATE
to	O
meet	O
the	O
demand	O
due	O
to	O
the	O
huge	O
domestic	O
consumption	O
market	O
.	O

 	O
Statistics	O
show	O
that	O
since	O
2017	B-DATE
,	O
the	O
annual	O
import	O
volume	O
of	O
bananas	B-CROP
in	O
China	B-GPE
has	O
been	O
above	O
one	O
million	O
tons	O
,	O
and	O
it	O
has	O
grown	O
at	O
a	O
relatively	O
high	O
rate	O
.	O

The	O
annual	O
growth	O
rates	O
in	O
2017	B-DATE
,	I-DATE
2018	I-DATE
and	I-DATE
2019	I-DATE
were	O
17.12	O
%	O
,	O
48.65	O
%	O
and	O
25.60	O
%	O
respectively	O
,	O
which	O
played	O
an	O
important	O
role	O
in	O
promoting	O
the	O
development	O
of	O
the	O
global	O
banana	B-CROP
trade	O
.	O

The	O
emerging	O
banana	B-CROP
importing	O
countries	O
represented	O
by	O
China	B-GPE
are	O
likely	O
to	O
replace	O
the	O
traditional	O
importing	O
countries	O
,	O
supporting	O
and	O
driving	O
the	O
development	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
banana	B-CROP
trade	O
.	O
 	O
On	O
August	B-DATE
2	I-DATE
,	I-DATE
2018	I-DATE
,	O

China	B-GPE
and	O
Cambodia	B-GPE
signed	O
the	O
Agreement	O
on	O
Phytosanitary	O
Requirements	O
for	O
Cambodian	B-GPE
Bananas	B-CROP
Exported	O
to	O
China	B-GPE
,	O
opening	O
the	O
door	O
for	O
Cambodian	B-GPE
bananas	B-CROP
to	O
enter	O
the	O
huge	O
Chinese	B-GPE
market	O
.	O

 	O
It	O
is	O
reported	O
that	O
banana	B-CROP
plantations	O
in	O
Cambodia	B-GPE
are	O
basically	O
not	O
affected	O
by	O
typhoons	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
light	O
and	O
heat	O
conditions	O
are	O
suitable	O
for	O
banana	B-CROP
growth	O
throughout	O
the	B-DATE
year	I-DATE
.	O

It	O
is	O
not	O
necessary	O
to	O
adjust	O
the	O
banana	B-CROP
budding	O
period	O
to	O
avoid	O
typhoons	O
and	O
cold	O
waves	O
,	O
as	O
in	O
China	B-GPE
.	O
It	O
is	O
a	O
rare	O
high	O
-	O
quality	O
banana	B-CROP
planting	O
area	O
.	O

But	O
for	B-DATE
years	I-DATE
,	O
Cambodian	B-GPE
banana	B-CROP
shipments	O
to	O
China	B-GPE
have	O
been	O
stranded	O
as	O
Cambodian	B-GPE
producers	O
and	O
exporters	O
failed	O
to	O
meet	O
China	B-GPE
's	O
stringent	O
sanitary	O
and	O
phytosanitary	O
requirements	O
.	O
 	O
At	O
the	O
same	O
time	O
,	O

before	O
entry	O
,	O
all	O
Cambodian	B-GPE
bananas	B-CROP
exported	O
to	O
China	B-GPE
could	O
only	O
be	O
transferred	O
to	O
China	B-GPE
through	O
Vietnam	B-GPE
(	O
a	O
third	O
country	O
)	O
after	O
meeting	O
the	O
requirements	O
.	O

The	O
freight	O
and	O
cost	O
were	O
relatively	O
high	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
export	O
volume	O
of	O
bananas	B-CROP
to	O
China	B-GPE
was	O
correspondingly	O
small	O
.	O
Now	O
,	O
with	O
the	O
completion	O
of	O
China	B-GPE
's	O
quarantine	O
and	O
inspection	O
procedures	O
,	O

Cambodian	B-GPE
bananas	B-CROP
are	O
officially	O
allowed	O
to	O
be	O
exported	O
to	O
China	B-GPE
,	O
and	O
they	O
can	O
be	O
directly	O
shipped	O
to	O
Chinese	B-GPE
ports	O
.	O

Cambodian	B-GPE
bananas	B-CROP
that	O
save	O
on	O
freight	O
will	O
be	O
more	O
competitive	O
in	O
the	O
market	O
.	O
 	O
Source	O
:	O
XHF.com	O

Plant	O
diseases	O
caused	O
by	O
viral	O
infection	O
are	O
affecting	O
all	O
major	O
crops	O
.	O
Being	O
an	O
obligate	O
intracellular	O
organisms	O
,	O
chemical	O
control	O
of	O
these	O
pathogens	O
is	O
so	O
far	O
not	O
applied	O
in	O
the	O
field	O
except	O
to	O
control	O
the	O
insect	O
vectors	O
of	O
the	O
viruses	O
.	O

Understanding	O
of	O
molecular	O
responses	O
of	O
plant	O
immunity	O
is	O
therefore	O
economically	O
important	O
,	O
guiding	O
the	O
enforcement	O
of	O
crop	O
resistance	O
.	O
To	O
disentangle	O
complex	O
regulatory	O
mechanisms	O
of	O
the	O
plant	O
immune	O
responses	O
,	O

understanding	O
system	O
as	O
a	O
whole	O
is	O
a	O
must	O
.	O

However	O
,	O
integrating	O
data	O
from	O
different	O
molecular	O
analysis	O
(	O
transcriptomics	O
,	O
proteomics	O
,	O
metabolomics	O
,	O
smallRNA	O
regulation	O
etc	O
.	O
)	O
is	O
not	O
straightforward	O
.	O
We	O
evaluated	O
the	O
response	O
of	O
potato	B-CROP
(	O
Solanum	B-CROP
tuberosum	I-CROP
L.	O
)	O
following	O
the	O
infection	O
with	O
potato	B-PATHOGEN
virus	I-PATHOGEN
Y	I-PATHOGEN
(	O
PVY	B-PATHOGEN
)	O
.	O

The	O
response	O
has	O
been	O
analyzed	O
on	O
two	O
molecular	O
levels	O
,	O
with	O
microarray	O
transcriptome	O
analysis	O
and	O
mass	O
spectroscopy	O
-	O
based	O
proteomics	O
.	O
Within	O
this	O
report	O
,	O
we	O
performed	O
detailed	O
analysis	O
of	O
the	O
results	O
on	O
both	O
levels	O
and	O
compared	O
two	O
different	O
approaches	O
for	O
analysis	O
of	O
proteomic	O
data	O
(	O
spectral	O
count	O
versus	O
MaxQuant	O
)	O
.	O

To	O
link	O
the	O
data	O
on	O
different	O
molecular	O
levels	O
,	O
each	O
protein	O
was	O
mapped	O
to	O
the	O
corresponding	O
potato	B-CROP
transcript	O
according	O
to	O
StNIB	O
paralogue	O
grouping	O
.	O
Only	O
33	O
%	O
of	O
the	O
proteins	O
mapped	O
to	O
microarray	O
probes	O
in	O
a	O
one	O
-	O
to	O
-	O
one	O
relation	O
and	O
additionally	O
many	O
showed	O
discordance	O
in	O
detected	O
levels	O
of	O
proteins	O
with	O
corresponding	O
transcripts	O
.	O

We	O
discussed	O
functional	O
importance	O
of	O
true	O
biological	O
differences	O
between	O
both	O
levels	O
and	O
showed	O
that	O
the	O
reason	O
for	O
the	O
discordance	O
between	O
transcript	O
and	O
protein	O
abundance	O
lies	O
partly	O
in	O
complexity	O
and	O
structure	O
of	O
biological	O
regulation	O
of	O
proteome	O
and	O
transcriptome	O
and	O
partly	O
in	O
technical	O
issues	O
contributing	O
to	O
it	O
.	O

Sweet	B-CROP
potato	I-CROP
(	O
Ipomoea	B-CROP
batatas	I-CROP
)	O
is	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
most	O
important	O
food	O
crops	O
worldwide	O
and	O
its	O
leaves	B-PLANT_PART
provide	O
a	O
dietary	O
source	O
of	O
nutrients	O
and	O
various	O
bioactive	O
compounds	O
.	O
These	O
constituents	O
of	O
sweet	B-CROP
potato	I-CROP
leaves	B-PLANT_PART
(	O
SPL	O
)	O
vary	O
among	O
varieties	O
and	O
play	O
important	O
roles	O
in	O
treating	O
and	O
preventing	O
various	O
diseases	O
.	O

Recently	O
,	O
more	O
attentions	O
in	O
health	O
-	O
promoting	O
benefits	O
have	O
led	O
to	O
several	O
in	O
vitro	O
and	O
in	O
vivo	O
investigations	O
,	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
the	O
identification	O
and	O
quantification	O
of	O
bioactive	O
compounds	O
in	O
SPL	O
.	O

Among	O
them	O
,	O
many	O
new	O
compounds	O
have	O
been	O
reported	O
as	O
the	O
first	O
identified	O
compounds	O
from	O
SPL	O
with	O
their	O
dominant	O
bioactivities	O
.	O
This	O
review	O
summarizes	O
the	O
current	O
knowledge	O
of	O
the	O
bioactive	O
compositions	O
of	O
SPL	O
and	O
their	O
health	O
benefits	O
.	O

Since	O
SPL	O
serve	O
as	O
a	O
potential	O
source	O
of	O
micronutrients	O
and	O
functional	O
compounds	O
,	O
they	O
can	O
be	O
further	O
developed	O
as	O
a	O
sustainable	O
crop	O
for	O
food	O
and	O
medicinal	O
industries	O
.	O

According	O
to	O
customs	O
data	O
,	O
China	B-GPE
imported	O
222,100	O
tons	O
of	O
bananas	B-CROP
(	O
222,100,375	O
kg	O
)	O
in	O
April	B-DATE
2022	I-DATE
,	O
with	O
an	O
import	O
value	O
of	O
US$	O
14,1673,434	O
.	O
Imports	O
increased	O
by	O
3.07	O
%	O
from	O
March	B-DATE
and	O
decreased	O
by	O
1.87	O
%	O
from	O
April	B-DATE
2021	I-DATE
;	O
the	O
cumulative	O
import	O
volume	O
from	O
January	B-DATE
to	I-DATE
April	I-DATE
2022	I-DATE
was	O
742,800	O
tons	O
(	O
742,849,127	O
kg	O
)	O
,	O

an	O
increase	O
of	O
10.41	O
%	O
from	O
the	O
same	O
period	O
in	O
2021	B-DATE
.	O

The	O
shipment	O
situation	O
at	O
various	O
ports	O
has	O
improved	O
slightly	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
Dongxing	B-GPE
port	O
of	O
China	B-GPE
and	O
Vietnam	B-GPE
,	O
which	O
has	O
been	O
closed	O
for	O
two	B-DATE
months	I-DATE
,	O
also	O
resumed	O
customs	O
clearance	O
in	O
late	B-DATE
April	I-DATE
.	O

 	O
The	O
average	O
import	O
price	O
of	O
bananas	B-CROP
in	O
April	B-DATE
2022	I-DATE
was	O
about	O
US$	O
637.88	O
/	O
ton	O
,	O
up	O
0.42	O
%	O
month	O
-	O
on	O
-	O
month	O
and	O
18.08	O
%	O
year	O
-	O
on	O
-	O
year	O
.	O

Affected	O
by	O
the	O
prevention	O
and	O
control	O
of	O
the	O
pandemic	O
,	O
some	O
foreign	O
producing	O
areas	O
have	O
experienced	O
poor	O
shipments	O
and	O
rising	O
freight	O
rates	O
.	O
In	O
some	O
production	O
bases	O
,	O
the	O
detention	O
of	O
bananas	B-CROP
is	O
serious	O
,	O

the	O
rate	O
of	O
high	O
-	O
quality	O
bananas	B-CROP
is	O
low	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
price	O
of	O
bananas	B-CROP
that	O
meet	O
the	O
export	O
standards	O
is	O
higher	O
than	O
that	O
of	O
the	O
same	O
period	O
last	B-DATE
year	I-DATE
.	O

 	O
In	O
April	B-DATE
2022	I-DATE
,	O
China	B-GPE
's	O
largest	O
source	O
of	O
imports	O
remained	O
Vietnam	B-GPE
,	O
accounting	O
for	O
42	O
%	O
,	O
an	O
increase	O
of	O
1	O
percentage	O
point	O
from	O
the	B-DATE
previous	I-DATE
month	I-DATE
.	O

The	O
second	O
and	O
third	O
places	O
are	O
the	O
Philippines	B-GPE
and	O
Cambodia	B-GPE
,	O
with	O
28	O
%	O
and	O
18	O
%	O
,	O
respectively	O
.	O
Affected	O
by	O
factors	O
such	O
as	O
Panama	B-DISEASE
disease	I-DISEASE
and	O
international	O
logistics	O
,	O

the	O
proportion	O
of	O
Philippine	O
bananas	B-CROP
in	O
the	O
Chinese	B-GPE
market	O
has	O
gradually	O
decreased	O
in	O
the	B-DATE
past	I-DATE
two	I-DATE
years	I-DATE
.	O

Coupled	O
with	O
the	O
impact	O
of	O
China	B-GPE
's	O
domestic	O
prevention	O
and	O
control	O
measures	O
,	O
port	O
transportation	O
is	O
not	O
smooth	O
.	O
 	O
Shanghai	B-GPE
Port	O
is	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
most	O
important	O
ports	O
for	O
Philippine	B-GPE
bananas	B-CROP
to	O
enter	O
China	B-GPE
.	O

Although	O
it	O
can	O
operate	O
normally	O
during	O
prevention	O
and	O
control	O
,	O
the	O
overall	O
container	O
volume	O
has	O
declined	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
vehicular	O
traffic	O
procedures	O
are	O
cumbersome	O
,	O
which	O
has	O
affected	O
the	O
entry	O
of	O
bananas	B-CROP
to	O
a	O
certain	O
extent	O
.	O

Cambodia	B-GPE
can	O
still	O
maintain	O
the	O
top	O
three	O
importing	O
countries	O
of	O
Chinese	B-GPE
bananas	B-CROP
,	O
but	O
due	O
to	O
the	O
lack	O
of	O
refrigeration	O
facilities	O
for	O
its	O
agricultural	O
products	O
,	O
and	O
with	O
the	O
strengthening	O
of	O
China	B-GPE
's	O
quarantine	O
policy	O
,	O

the	O
supply	O
of	O
domestic	O
production	O
areas	O
has	O
gradually	O
increased	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
next	O
period	O
of	O
time	O
,	O
the	O
export	O
of	O
Cambodian	B-GPE
bananas	B-CROP
to	O
China	B-GPE
will	O
not	O
be	O
positive	O
.	O
 	O
Source	O
:	O
Mysteel	O

Cassava	B-CROP
is	O
consumed	O
in	O
the	B-GPE
Democratic	I-GPE
Republic	I-GPE
of	I-GPE
Congo	I-GPE
(	O
DRC	B-GPE
)	O
as	O
a	O
staple	O
food	O
for	O
the	O
majority	O
of	O
the	O
Congolese	B-GPE
population	O
.	O
This	O
crop	O
is	O
used	O
in	O
several	O
forms	O
:	O
as	O
fufu	O
,	O

chikwangue	O
and	O
pondu	O
;	O
cassava	B-CROP
leaves	B-PLANT_PART
are	O
the	O
most	O
consumed	O
vegetable	O
in	O
the	O
country	O
.	O

 	O
In	O
2002	B-DATE
,	O
cassava	B-CROP
root	B-PLANT_PART
symptoms	O
similar	O
to	O
cassava	B-DISEASE
brown	I-DISEASE
streak	I-DISEASE
disease	I-DISEASE
(	O
CBSD	B-DISEASE
)	O
were	O
reported	O
for	O
the	O
first	O
time	O
in	O
western	B-LOC
DRC	I-LOC
.	O
PCR	O
assays	O
,	O
using	O
primers	O
specific	O
to	O
Cassava	B-PATHOGEN
brown	I-PATHOGEN
streak	I-PATHOGEN
virus	I-PATHOGEN
(	O
CBSV	B-PATHOGEN
)	O
,	O

failed	O
to	O
detect	O
or	O
identify	O
any	O
viral	O
pathogens	O
in	O
diseased	O
cassava	B-CROP
samples	O
from	O
western	B-LOC
DRC	I-LOC
.	O

Therefore	O
,	O
next	O
generation	O
sequencing	O
(	O
NGS	O
)	O
techniques	O
were	O
used	O
as	O
they	O
are	O
able	O
to	O
sequence	O
full	O
organism	O
genomes	O
and	O
are	O
widely	O
used	O
for	O
the	O
identification	O
of	O
pathogens	O
responsible	O
for	O
new	O
diseases	O
.	O

The	O
main	O
objective	O
of	O
this	O
study	O
was	O
to	O
identify	O
the	O
pathogens	O
causing	O
root	B-SYMPTOM
necrosis	I-SYMPTOM
in	O
western	B-LOC
DRC	I-LOC
.	O
 	O
Whatman	O
®	O
FTA	O
™	O
cards	O
were	O
used	O
to	O
collect	O
12	O
cassava	B-CROP
leaf	B-PLANT_PART
samples	O
from	O
plants	O
with	O
symptoms	O
indicative	O
of	O
very	O
severe	O
root	B-SYMPTOM
necrosis	I-SYMPTOM
,	O

as	O
well	O
as	O
two	O
asymptomatic	O
samples	O
.	O

No	O
viruses	O
(	O
including	O
CBSV	B-PATHOGEN
)	O
were	O
found	O
in	O
any	O
of	O
the	O
DRC	B-GPE
samples	O
.	O
These	O
preliminary	O
results	O
confirm	O
all	O
the	O
previous	O
negative	O
results	O
obtained	O
using	O
PCR	O
and	O
CBSV	B-PATHOGEN
primers	O
.	O

Guatemala	B-GPE
has	O
recently	O
stripped	O
the	O
Philippines	B-GPE
of	O
its	O
status	O
as	O
the	O
world	O
's	O
second	O
-	O
largest	O
exporter	O
of	O
bananas	B-CROP
.	O
Based	O
on	O
data	O
from	O
the	B-ORG
Food	I-ORG
and	I-ORG
Agriculture	I-ORG
Organization	I-ORG
of	I-ORG
the	I-ORG
United	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
,	O

the	O
Central	B-LOC
American	I-LOC
nation	O
has	O
overtaken	O
the	O
Philippines	B-GPE
in	O
terms	O
of	O
banana	B-CROP
exports	O
last	B-DATE
year	I-DATE
.	O

 	O
In	O
a	O
report	O
,	O
FAO	B-ORG
estimated	O
that	O
Guatemala	B-GPE
exported	O
a	O
total	O
of	O
2.467	O
million	O
tons	O
of	O
bananas	B-CROP
last	B-DATE
year	I-DATE
,	O
eclipsing	O
the	O
Philippines	B-GPE
's	O
2.235	O
mln	O
tons	O
.	O
The	O
UN	B-ORG
body	O
noted	O
that	O
Philippine	O
banana	B-CROP
growers	O
are	O
grappling	O
with	O
the	O
spread	O
of	O
Fusarium	B-DISEASE
wilt	I-DISEASE
or	O
Panama	B-DISEASE
disease	I-DISEASE
,	O

which	O
could	O
wipe	O
out	O
entire	O
banana	B-CROP
plantations	O
.	O

The	O
spike	O
in	O
the	O
cost	O
of	O
inputs	O
and	O
fertilizers	O
,	O
which	O
was	O
largely	O
caused	O
by	O
the	O
conflict	O
in	O
Eastern	B-LOC
Europe	I-LOC
,	O
has	O
also	O
made	O
it	O
difficult	O
for	O
traders	O
to	O
keep	O
the	O
price	O
of	O
the	O
crop	O
at	O
an	O
affordable	O
level	O
.	O

 	O
Apart	O
from	O
coconut	B-CROP
oil	O
,	O
banana	B-CROP
is	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
major	O
agricultural	O
export	O
earners	O
of	O
the	O
Philippines	B-GPE
.	O
Based	O
on	O
data	O
from	O
the	O
Philippine	B-ORG
Statistics	I-ORG
Authority	I-ORG
(	O
PSA	B-ORG
)	O
,	O

the	O
country	O
's	O
banana	B-CROP
exports	O
reached	O
$	O
1.096	O
billion	O
last	B-DATE
year	I-DATE
,	O
second	O
only	O
to	O
shipments	O
of	O
coconut	B-CROP
oil	O
,	O
which	O
reached	O
more	O
than	O
$	O
2	O
billion	O
.	O

However	O
,	O
export	O
receipts	O
from	O
bananas	B-CROP
recorded	O
in	O
2022	B-DATE
were	O
nearly	O
4	O
percent	O
lower	O
than	O
the	B-DATE
previous	I-DATE
year	I-DATE
's	O
$	O
1.138	O
billion	O
.	O
 	O
Banana	B-CROP
growers	O
and	O
exporters	O
belonging	O
to	O
the	O
Pilipino	B-ORG
Banana	I-ORG
Growers	I-ORG
and	I-ORG
Exporters	I-ORG
Association	I-ORG
are	O
banking	O
on	O
the	O
campaign	O
promise	O
of	O
the	O
President	O
,	O

who	O
is	O
concurrent	O
agriculture	O
chief	O
,	O
that	O
a	O
state	O
-	O
of	O
-	O
the	O
-	O
art	O
Banana	B-ORG
Research	I-ORG
and	I-ORG
Development	I-ORG
Center	I-ORG
would	O
be	O
set	O
up	O
during	O
his	O
term	O
.	O

 	O
Source	O
:	O
businessmirror.com.ph	O

Cassava	B-DISEASE
brown	I-DISEASE
streak	I-DISEASE
disease	I-DISEASE
is	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
latest	O
outbreaks	O
of	O
diseases	O
threatening	O
cassava	B-CROP
production	O
in	O
Uganda	B-GPE
.	O
Although	O
,	O
previously	O
reported	O
in	O
some	O
parts	O
of	O
east	B-LOC
African	I-LOC
coast	I-LOC
,	O

Since	O
,	O
its	O
first	O
reported	O
outbreak	O
in	O
mid	B-DATE
2000s	I-DATE
,	O
CBSD	B-DISEASE
has	O
continued	O
to	O
spread	O
in	O
many	O
cassava	B-CROP
growing	O
districts	O
of	O
Uganda	B-GPE
.	O
Cassava	B-DISEASE
brown	I-DISEASE
streak	I-DISEASE
disease	I-DISEASE
manifests	O
as	O
a	O
syndrome	O
characterised	O
by	O
leaf	B-SYMPTOM
chlorosis	I-SYMPTOM
,	O

stem	B-SYMPTOM
and	I-SYMPTOM
root	I-SYMPTOM
necrosis	I-SYMPTOM
.	O

Semi	O
-	O
structure	O
questionnaires	O
were	O
used	O
to	O
gather	O
information	O
from	O
180	O
respondents	O
from	O
the	O
districts	O
of	O
Mukono	B-GPE
,	O
Masaka	B-GPE
and	O
Wakiso	B-GPE
on	O
the	O
knowledge	O
and	O
perception	O
of	O
CBSD	B-DISEASE
.	O
The	O
findings	O
revealed	O
that	O
cassava	B-CROP
was	O
widely	O
grown	O
in	O
the	O
three	O
districts	O
.	O

However	O
,	O
a	O
number	O
of	O
constraints	O
including	O
pests	O
and	O
diseases	O
were	O
reported	O
to	O
be	O
affecting	O
cassava	B-CROP
growing	O
.	O
Of	O
the	O
diseases	O
,	O
CBSD	B-DISEASE
was	O
ranked	O
as	O
the	O
most	O
widespread	O
and	O
devastating	O
.	O

rotting	B-SYMPTOM
and	I-SYMPTOM
necrosis	I-SYMPTOM
of	I-SYMPTOM
the	I-SYMPTOM
root	I-SYMPTOM
tubers	I-SYMPTOM
.	O

Both	O
the	O
old	O
and	O
newly	O
introduced	O
cassava	B-CROP
varieties	O
were	O
susceptible	O
to	O
CBSD	B-DISEASE
.	O
Accordingly	O
,	O
CBSD	B-DISEASE
was	O
thought	O
of	O
as	O
responsible	O
for	O
food	O
insecurity	O
,	O
livelihoods	O
and	O
the	O
loss	O
of	O
cassava	B-CROP
biodiversity	O
among	O
others	O
.	O

Cassava	B-CROP
is	O
a	O
main	O
staple	O
food	O
for	O
800	O
million	O
people	O
world	O
-	O
wide	O
.	O
Production	O
is	O
limited	O
by	O
pest	O
and	O
pathogens	O
.	O
The	O
most	O
devastating	O
cassava	B-PATHOGEN
viruses	I-PATHOGEN
are	O
Cassava	B-DISEASE
Brown	I-DISEASE
Streak	I-DISEASE
Virus	I-DISEASE
and	O
Uganda	B-PATHOGEN
Cassava	I-PATHOGEN
Brown	I-PATHOGEN
Streak	I-PATHOGEN
Virusboth	I-PATHOGEN
causing	O
severe	B-SYMPTOM
root	I-SYMPTOM
necrosis	I-SYMPTOM
called	O
Cassava	B-DISEASE
Brown	I-DISEASE
Streak	I-DISEASE
Disease	I-DISEASE
.	O

In	O
the	B-DATE
last	I-DATE
10	I-DATE
years	I-DATE
,	O
the	O
Cassava	B-DISEASE
Brown	I-DISEASE
Streak	I-DISEASE
Disease	I-DISEASE
(	O
CBSD)has	B-DISEASE
spread	O
across	O
Africa	B-LOC
from	O
the	O
east	B-LOC
coast	I-LOC
of	I-LOC
Africa	I-LOC
to	O
central	B-LOC
Africa	I-LOC
.	O
Similar	O
root	B-SYMPTOM
necrosis	I-SYMPTOM
to	O
cassava	B-DISEASE
brown	I-DISEASE
streak	I-DISEASE
disease	I-DISEASE
has	O
also	O
been	O
identified	O
in	O
the	B-GPE
Democratic	I-GPE
Republic	I-GPE
of	I-GPE
Congo	I-GPE
where	O
the	O
first	O
symptoms	O
were	O
identified	O
in	O
2002	B-DATE
in	O
Kinshasa	B-GPE
and	O
Kongo	B-GPE
central	I-GPE
province	I-GPE
.	O

In	O
2012	B-DATE
,	O
the	O
presence	O
of	O
CBSD	B-DISEASE
was	O
confirmed	O
in	O
eastern	B-LOC
Democratic	I-LOC
Republic	I-LOC
of	I-LOC
Congo	I-LOC
.	O
All	O
attempts	O
since	O
2002	B-DATE
in	O
western	B-LOC
Democratic	I-LOC
Republic	I-LOC
of	I-LOC
Congo	I-LOC
to	O
identify	O
the	O
cause	O
of	O
these	O
root	B-SYMPTOM
necrosis	I-SYMPTOM
have	O
failed	O
.	O

In	O
2017	B-DATE
,	O
a	O
team	O
of	O
scientists	O
surveying	O
the	O
Songololo	B-GPE
Territory	I-GPE
in	O
the	O
Kongo	B-GPE
central	I-GPE
province	I-GPE
at	O
the	O
northern	B-LOC
Angola	I-LOC
,	O
identified	O
the	O
same	O
root	B-SYMPTOM
necrosis	I-SYMPTOM
similar	O
to	O
CBSD	B-DISEASE
in	O
several	O
localities	O
bordering	O
Angola	B-GPE
.	O

These	O
unexpected	O
results	O
will	O
foreshadow	O
the	O
presence	O
of	O
cassava	B-DISEASE
root	I-DISEASE
necrosis	I-DISEASE
in	O
Angola	B-GPE
.	O
This	O
preliminary	O
investigation	O
in	O
northern	B-LOC
Angola	I-LOC
was	O
conducted	O
specifically	O
in	O
the	O
Zaire	B-GPE
province	I-GPE
and	O
the	O
territory	O
of	O
Mbanza	B-LOC
Kongo	I-LOC
at	O
approximatively	O
62	O
kms	O
from	O
the	B-GPE
Democratic	I-GPE
Republic	I-GPE
of	I-GPE
Congo	I-GPE
border	O
in	O
order	O
to	O
verify	O
,	O

whether	O
or	O
not	O
,	O
these	O
root	B-SYMPTOM
necrosis	I-SYMPTOM
are	O
present	O
in	O
Angola	B-GPE
.	O

Results	O
obtained	O
from	O
this	O
exploratory	O
survey	O
in	O
several	O
fields	O
of	O
the	O
Zaire	B-GPE
province	I-GPE
and	O
territory	O
of	O
Mbanza	B-LOC
Kongo	I-LOC
confirmed	O
,	O
for	O
the	O
first	O
time	O
,	O
the	O
presence	O
of	O
cassava	B-DISEASE
root	I-DISEASE
necrosis	I-DISEASE
in	O
Angola	B-GPE
,	O

similar	O
to	O
CBSD	B-DISEASE
,	O
as	O
identified	O
in	O
western	B-LOC
DRC	I-LOC

Cassava	B-CROP
,	O
a	O
food	O
security	O
crop	O
in	O
Africa	B-LOC
,	O
is	O
grown	O
throughout	O
the	O
tropics	B-LOC
and	I-LOC
subtropics	I-LOC
.	O
Although	O
cassava	B-CROP
can	O
provide	O
high	O
productivity	O
in	O
suboptimal	O
conditions	O
,	O
the	O
yield	O
in	O
Africa	B-LOC
is	O
substantially	O
lower	O
than	O
in	O
other	O
geographies	O
.	O

The	O
yield	O
gap	O
is	O
attributable	O
to	O
many	O
challenges	O
faced	O
by	O
cassava	B-CROP
in	O
Africa	B-LOC
,	O
including	O
susceptibility	O
to	O
diseases	O
and	O
poor	O
soil	O
conditions	O
.	O
In	O
this	O
study	O
,	O
we	O
carried	O
out	O
3'RNA	O
sequencing	O
on	O
150	O
accessions	O
from	O
the	O
National	B-ORG
Crops	I-ORG
Resources	I-ORG
Research	I-ORG
Institute	I-ORG
,	O

Uganda	B-GPE
for	O
5	O
tissue	O
types	O
,	O
providing	O
population	O
-	O
based	O
transcriptomics	O
resources	O
to	O
the	O
research	O
community	O
in	O
a	O
web	O
-	O
based	O
queryable	O
cassava	B-CROP
expression	O
atlas	O
.	O

Differential	O
expression	O
and	O
weighted	O
gene	O
co	O
-	O
expression	O
network	O
analysis	O
were	O
performed	O
to	O
detect	O
8820	O
significantly	O
differentially	O
expressed	O
genes	O
(	O
DEGs	O
)	O
,	O
revealing	O
similarity	O
in	O
expression	O
patterns	O
between	O
tissue	O
types	O
and	O
the	O
clustering	O
of	O
detected	O
DEGs	O
into	O
18	O
gene	O
modules	O
.	O

As	O
a	O
confirmation	O
of	O
data	O
quality	O
,	O
differential	O
expression	O
and	O
pathway	O
analysis	O
targeting	O
cassava	B-DISEASE
mosaic	I-DISEASE
disease	I-DISEASE
(	O
CMD	B-DISEASE
)	O
identified	O
27	O
genes	O
observed	O
in	O
the	O
plant	O
–	O
pathogen	O
interaction	O
pathway	O
,	O

several	O
previously	O
identified	O
CMD	B-DISEASE
resistance	O
genes	O
,	O
and	O
two	O
peroxidase	O
family	O
proteins	O
different	O
from	O
the	O
CMD2	O
gene	O
.	O

Present	O
research	O
work	O
represents	O
a	O
novel	O
resource	O
towards	O
understanding	O
complex	O
traits	O
at	O
expression	O
and	O
molecular	O
levels	O
for	O
the	O
development	O
of	O
resistant	O
and	O
high	O
-	O
yielding	O
cassava	B-CROP
varieties	O
,	O
as	O
exemplified	O
with	O
CMD	B-DISEASE
.	O

251	O
,	O
pag	O
.	O
267	O
-	O
275	O
.	O

Plantain	B-CROP
banana	I-CROP
is	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
staple	O
foods	O
of	O
the	O
African	B-LOC
continent	O
,	O
but	O
there	O
are	O
many	O
reasons	O
why	O
it	O
is	O
unprofitable	O
to	O
grow	O
plantain	B-CROP
in	O
South	B-GPE
Africa	I-GPE
.	O
 	O

Plantains	B-CROP
are	O
fruits	B-PLANT_PART
that	O
are	O
similar	O
to	O
bananas	B-CROP
,	O
but	O
they	O
have	O
more	O
starch	O
and	O
a	O
thicker	O
skin	O
.	O

They	O
are	O
also	O
eaten	O
in	O
many	O
forms	O
and	O
are	O
nutrient	O
-	O
dense	O
.	O
 	O
Though	O
plantains	B-CROP
are	O
similar	O
to	O
bananas	B-CROP
and	O
Africa	B-LOC
,	O
as	O
a	O
whole	O
,	O
produces	O
the	O
majority	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
's	O
banana	B-CROP
and	O
plantain	B-CROP
fruits	B-PLANT_PART
,	O

South	B-GPE
Africa	I-GPE
does	O
not	O
grow	O
plantains	B-CROP
.	O

The	O
main	O
reason	O
for	O
this	O
is	O
that	O
diseases	O
,	O
pests	O
,	O
and	O
sub	O
-	O
par	O
conditions	O
mean	O
that	O
planting	O
plantains	B-CROP
is	O
not	O
profitable	O
enough	O
for	O
the	O
country	O
.	O
 	O
What	O
are	O
plantains	B-CROP
used	O
for	O
?	O

 	O
Plantains	B-CROP
have	O
a	O
bit	O
more	O
starch	O
than	O
bananas	B-CROP
and	O
are	O
a	O
bit	O
longer	O
and	O
firmer	O
than	O
bananas	B-CROP
.	O
Although	O
plantains	B-CROP
are	O
not	O
as	O
sweet	O
as	O
bananas	B-CROP
,	O
they	O
are	O
often	O
enjoyed	O
in	O
their	O
fresh	O
,	O

fruity	O
form	O
or	O
in	O
a	O
variety	O
of	O
other	O
forms	O
like	O
puree	O
,	O
flour	O
,	O
jam	O
,	O
jelly	O
,	O
chips	O
,	O
catsup	O
,	O
relishes	O
or	O
spreads	O
,	O
preserves	O
,	O
vinegar	O
,	O

and	O
even	O
wine	O
.	O

Plantain	B-CROP
is	O
also	O
enjoyed	O
in	O
both	O
unripe	O
and	O
ripe	O
form	O
,	O
which	O
makes	O
it	O
an	O
incredibly	O
versatile	O
addition	O
to	O
cuisine	O
.	O
 	O
Bananas	B-CROP
and	O
plantains	B-CROP
constitute	O
a	O
large	O
proportion	O
of	O
the	O
staple	O
food	O
sources	O
in	O
Africa	B-LOC
.	O

Within	O
Africa	B-LOC
,	O
the	O
countries	O
that	O
produce	O
the	O
most	O
plantains	B-CROP
are	O
Ghana	B-GPE
,	O
Nigeria	B-GPE
,	O
Cote	B-GPE
d'Ivoire	I-GPE
,	O
and	O
Guinea	B-GPE
 	O
Why	O
South	B-GPE
Africa	I-GPE
does	O
not	O
grow	O
plantain	B-CROP
banana	B-CROP
 	O

Even	O
though	O
Africa	B-LOC
,	O
as	O
a	O
whole	O
,	O
is	O
responsible	O
for	O
over	O
a	O
third	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
's	O
banana	B-CROP
and	O
plantain	B-CROP
production	O
,	O
plantains	B-CROP
are	O
not	O
produced	O
in	O
South	B-GPE
Africa	I-GPE
,	O

specifically	O
.	O

Bananas	B-CROP
and	O
plantains	B-CROP
are	O
quite	O
important	O
crops	O
in	O
the	O
African	B-GPE
continent	O
,	O
especially	O
because	O
these	O
fruits	B-PLANT_PART
are	O
nutrient	O
-	O
dense	O
,	O
with	O
high	O
quantities	O
of	O
carbohydrates	O
.	O
The	O
Southern	B-LOC
part	I-LOC
of	O
Africa	B-LOC
produces	O
over	O
20	O
million	O
tons	O
of	O
bananas	B-CROP
and	O
plantains	B-CROP
annually	O
.	O

 	O
However	O
,	O
only	O
about	O
one	O
percent	O
of	O
this	O
total	O
amount	O
is	O
exported	O
to	O
other	O
parts	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
.	O
Thus	O
,	O
even	O
though	O
South	B-GPE
Africa	I-GPE
is	O
part	O
of	O
the	O
few	O
countries	O
that	O
export	O
their	O
bananas	B-CROP
,	O

plantains	B-CROP
are	O
not	O
exported	O
because	O
they	O
are	O
not	O
grown	O
within	O
the	O
country	O
.	O

 	O
There	O
are	O
many	O
reasons	O
why	O
plantains	B-CROP
are	O
not	O
being	O
produced	O
in	O
South	B-GPE
Africa	I-GPE
,	O
but	O
the	O
overarching	O
reason	O
is	O
seemingly	O
that	O
it	O
is	O
just	O
not	O
profitable	O
enough	O
to	O
grow	O
them	O
.	O

Plantains	B-CROP
are	O
often	O
grown	O
in	O
small	O
family	O
-	O
type	O
farm	O
operations	O
which	O
means	O
that	O
these	O
farms	O
will	O
not	O
be	O
able	O
to	O
produce	O
and	O
sell	O
enough	O
plantains	B-CROP
to	O
justify	O
the	O
costs	O
of	O
the	O
plantation	O
.	O

 	O
There	O
are	O
also	O
other	O
reasons	O
why	O
growing	O
plantains	B-CROP
in	O
South	B-LOC
Africa	I-LOC
is	O
unfeasible	O
,	O
including	O
diseases	O
,	O
pests	O
,	O
and	O
abiotic	O
stress	O
that	O
could	O
come	O
with	O
growing	O
them	O
.	O

 	O
Why	O
diseases	O
make	O
growing	O
plantain	B-CROP
in	O
South	B-GPE
Africa	I-GPE
difficult	O
 	O
One	O
of	O
the	O
main	O
reasons	O
why	O
it	O
is	O
difficult	O
for	O
farmers	O
to	O
grow	O
plantains	B-CROP
in	O
South	B-GPE
Africa	I-GPE
is	O
the	O
number	O
of	O
diseases	O
that	O
are	O
found	O
in	O
the	O
country	O
and	O
that	O
were	O
likely	O
introduced	O
by	O
other	O
infected	O
plants	O
.	O

Diseases	O
caused	O
by	O
fungus	O
such	O
as	O
black	B-DISEASE
Sigatoka	I-DISEASE
and	O
yellow	B-DISEASE
Sigatoka	I-DISEASE
result	O
in	O
early	B-SYMPTOM
leaf	I-SYMPTOM
death	I-SYMPTOM
and	O
lower	B-SYMPTOM
yields	I-SYMPTOM
,	O
with	O
crop	O
losses	O
caused	O
by	O
these	O
diseases	O
being	O
as	O
high	O
as	O
75	O
percent	O
.	O

 	O
There	O
are	O
also	O
diseases	O
such	O
as	O
Banana	B-PATHOGEN
Bunchy	I-PATHOGEN
Top	I-PATHOGEN
Virus	I-PATHOGEN
that	O
can	O
spread	O
quickly	O
through	O
a	O
plantation	O
,	O
and	O
Banana	B-PATHOGEN
Streak	I-PATHOGEN
Virus	I-PATHOGEN
,	O
which	O
is	O
embedded	O
in	O
a	O
plant	O
's	O
genome	O
and	O
can	O
not	O
be	O
spread	O
.	O

 	O
The	O
prevalence	O
of	O
these	O
diseases	O
in	O
South	B-GPE
Africa	I-GPE
means	O
it	O
may	O
be	O
too	O
much	O
of	O
a	O
risk	O
for	O
farmers	O
to	O
plant	O
plantains	B-CROP
,	O
as	O
they	O
risk	O
losing	O
a	O
large	O
percentage	O
of	O
their	O
investment	O
to	O
the	O
above	O
-	O
mentioned	O
diseases	O
.	O

 	O
Why	O
pests	O
make	O
growing	O
plantain	B-CROP
in	O
South	B-GPE
Africa	I-GPE
difficult	O
 	O
Additionally	O
to	O
the	O
prevalence	O
of	O
several	O
diseases	O
,	O
there	O
are	O
also	O
pests	O
that	O
could	O
lead	O
to	O
crop	O
loss	O
,	O

which	O
is	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
reasons	O
why	O
plantains	B-CROP
are	O
not	O
grown	O
in	O
South	B-LOC
Africa	I-LOC
.	O

 	O
Here	O
,	O
the	O
banana	O
weevil	O
is	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
most	O
prevalent	O
insect	O
pests	O
in	O
banana	B-CROP
and	O
plantain	B-CROP
plantations	O
in	O
Africa	B-LOC
.	O
When	O
a	O
plantation	O
is	O
infected	O
with	O
banana	O
weevil	O
,	O

the	O
plantain	B-CROP
crops	O
have	O
considerably	O
less	O
yield	O
,	O
which	O
,	O
in	O
turn	O
,	O
leads	O
to	O
less	O
sales	O
and	O
income	O
for	O
the	O
farm	O
.	O

 	O
Why	O
abiotic	O
stress	O
makes	O
growing	O
plantain	B-CROP
in	O
South	B-GPE
Africa	I-GPE
difficult	O
 	O
Bananas	B-CROP
and	O
plantains	B-CROP
are	O
tropical	O
crops	O
which	O
means	O
that	O
they	O
need	O
high	O
humidity	O
,	O
constant	O
high	O
temperatures	O
,	O

and	O
high	O
levels	O
of	O
rainfall	O
to	O
grow	O
at	O
their	O
optimal	O
potential	O
.	O

However	O
,	O
South	B-GPE
Africa	I-GPE
has	O
a	O
sub	B-LOC
-	I-LOC
tropical	I-LOC
climate	O
,	O
meaning	O
that	O
plantains	B-CROP
will	O
not	O
have	O
ideal	O
conditions	O
to	O
grow	O
in	O
the	O
country	O
.	O
Growing	O
them	O
could	O
lead	O
to	O
sub	O
-	O
standard	O
crops	O
that	O
do	O
not	O
sell	O
well	O
or	O
sell	O
and	O
are	O
not	O
profitable	O
enough	O
to	O
sustain	O
the	O
plantation	O
and	O
workers	O
on	O
it	O
.	O

 	O
There	O
are	O
also	O
factors	O
like	O
drought	O
,	O
wind	O
,	O
chilling	O
,	O
and	O
nutritional	O
deficiencies	O
that	O
farmers	O
need	O
to	O
consider	O
before	O
they	O
plant	O
plantains	B-CROP
,	O
and	O
these	O
may	O
be	O
contributing	O
factors	O
to	O
why	O
many	O
farmers	O
decide	O
not	O
to	O
plant	O
them	O
.	O

,	O

2014	B-DATE
)	O
.	O
In	O
November	B-DATE
2021	I-DATE
,	O
leaf	B-SYMPTOM
blight	I-SYMPTOM
symptoms	O
were	O
observed	O
on	O
South	B-LOC
China	I-LOC
6	O
(	O
SC6	O
)	O
cassava	B-CROP
plants	O
in	O
Haikou	B-GPE
City	I-GPE
,	O
Hainan	B-GPE
Province	I-GPE
,	O
China	B-GPE
.	O

The	O
disease	O
was	O
presented	O
in	O
almost	O
every	O
cassava	B-CROP
plant	O
we	O
observed	O
.	O
The	O
rotten	B-SYMPTOM
leaves	I-SYMPTOM
were	O
shown	O
to	O
be	O
infected	O
but	O
not	O
the	O
root	B-PLANT_PART
or	O
stem	B-PLANT_PART
.	O
The	O
lesions	O
started	O
on	O
the	O
plant	O
's	O
lower	O
leaves	B-PLANT_PART
and	O
gradually	O
developed	O
on	O
the	O
upper	O
leaves	B-PLANT_PART
of	O
the	O
entire	O
cassava	B-CROP
plant	O
.	O

The	O
infected	O
leaves	B-PLANT_PART
gradually	O
withered	B-SYMPTOM
.	O
Microscopic	O
observation	O
showed	O
that	O
the	O
infected	O
leaves	B-PLANT_PART
exhibited	O
necrotic	B-SYMPTOM
lesions	I-SYMPTOM
with	O
pycnidial	O
structures	O
all	O
over	O
their	O
surface	O
.	O
Diseased	O
leaf	B-PLANT_PART
segments	O
(	O
4	O
×	O
4	O
mm	O
)	O
were	O
disinfected	O
for	O
30	B-DATE
seconds	I-DATE
with	O
sodium	O
hypochlorite	O
1	O
%	O
solution	O
and	O
then	O
rinsed	O
with	O
sterile	O
water	O
for	O
30	B-DATE
seconds	I-DATE
before	O
being	O
placed	O
on	O
potato	O
dextrose	O
agar	O
(	O
PDA	O
)	O
medium	O
.	O

Plates	O
were	O
incubated	O
at	O
28	O
°	O
C	O
in	O
complete	O
darkness	O
.	O
Marginal	O
hyphae	O
were	O
picked	O
and	O
placed	O
on	O
a	O
new	O
PDA	O
medium	O
,	O
and	O
pure	O
cultures	O
were	O
obtained	O
after	O
multiple	O
transfers	O
.	O

The	O
hyphae	O
started	O
white	O
and	O
gradually	O
changed	O
to	O
a	O
fluffy	O
black	O
-	O
gray	O
color	O
as	O
it	O
grew	O
on	O
the	O
PDA	O
.	O
Microscopic	O
observation	O
showed	O
that	O
there	O
were	O
a	O
large	O
number	O
of	O
ellipsoidal	O
microsclerotia	O
between	O
the	O
hyphae	O
.	O

Microsclerotia	O
were	O
sub	O
fusiform	O
,	O
and	O
hyaline	O
,	O
with	O
a	O
length	O
of	O
about	O
40	O
μm	O
.	O
The	O
ribosomal	O
internal	O
transcribed	O
spacer	O
(	O
ITS	O
)	O
region	O
,	O
ribosomal	O
small	O
subunit	O
(	O
SSU	O
)	O
region	O
,	O

and	O
ribosomal	O
large	O
subunit	O
(	O
LSU	O
)	O
region	O
of	O
the	O
isolate	O
were	O
amplified	O
and	O
sequenced	O
using	O
primers	O
ITS1	O
and	O
ITS4	O
,	O
NS1	O
and	O
NS4	O
(	O
White	O
et	O
al	O
.	O
,	O

1990	B-DATE
)	O
,	O
and	O
LROR	O
and	O
LR5	O
(	O
Moriya	O
et	O
al	O
.	O
,	O
2005	B-DATE
)	O
,	O
respectively	O
.	O
The	O
obtained	O
ITS	O
(	O
GenBank	B-ORG
accession	O
no	O
.	O
OP185242	O
)	O
,	O
SSU	B-ORG
(	O
GenBank	B-ORG
accession	O
no	O
.	O

OQ165195	O
)	O
,	O
and	O
LSU	O
(	O
GenBank	B-ORG
accession	O
no	O
.	O
OQ118350.1	O
)	O
had	O
99.8	O
%	O
(	O
100	O
%	O
coverage	O
)	O
,	O
100	O
%	O
(	O
100	O
%	O
coverage	O
)	O
,	O
and	O
100	O
%	O
(	O
100	O
%	O
coverage	O
)	O
identities	O
with	O
the	O
references	O
ITS	O
(	O
GenBank	B-ORG
accession	O
no	O
.	O

KF951698	O
)	O
,	O
SSU	B-ORG
(	O
GenBank	B-ORG
accession	O
no	O
.	O
KF766281.1	O
)	O
,	O
and	O
LSU	O
(	O
GenBank	B-ORG
accession	O
no	O
.	O
KF766364.1	O
)	O
in	O
Macrophomina	B-PATHOGEN
phaseolina	I-PATHOGEN
,	O
respectively	O
.	O
A	O
phylogenetic	O
tree	O
was	O
constructed	O
with	O
software	O
MEGA7	O
using	O
the	O
maximum	O
likelihood	O
method	O
,	O

showing	O
that	O
the	O
isolate	O
was	O
grouped	O
in	O
the	O
same	O
clade	O
as	O
M.	B-PATHOGEN
phaseolina	I-PATHOGEN
.	O

To	O
prove	O
Koch	O
's	O
postulates	O
,	O
five	O
healthy	O
SC6	O
cassava	B-CROP
plants	O
(	O
2	B-DATE
-	I-DATE
month	I-DATE
-	I-DATE
old	I-DATE
)	O
with	O
4	O
-	O
6	O
leaves	B-PLANT_PART
were	O
wounded	O
with	O
a	O
small	O
pin	O
and	O
inoculated	O
with	O
PDA	O
blocks	O
(	O
3	O
×	O
3	O
mm	O
)	O
excised	O
from	O
the	O
margin	O
of	O
a	O
7	B-DATE
-	I-DATE
day	I-DATE
-	O
cultured	O
colony	O
(	O
Hu	O
et	O
al	O
.	O

,	O

2022	B-DATE
)	O
.	O
Healthy	O
plants	O
treated	O
with	O
sterile	O
PDA	O
plugs	O
served	O
as	O
controls	O
.	O
All	O
plants	O
were	O
grown	O
at	O
25	O
°	O
C	O
with	O
a	O
12	B-DATE
-	I-DATE
h	I-DATE
light	O
/	O
dark	O
rotation	O
.	O

After	O
7	B-DATE
days	I-DATE
,	O
typical	O
blight	B-SYMPTOM
symptoms	O
developed	O
on	O
leaves	B-PLANT_PART
inoculated	O
with	O
M.	B-PATHOGEN
phaseolina	I-PATHOGEN
,	O
but	O
not	O
on	O
the	O
controls	O
.	O
The	O
fungus	O
was	O
isolated	O
from	O
infected	O
leaves	B-PLANT_PART
.	O
Based	O
on	O
molecular	O
identification	O
,	O

M.	B-PATHOGEN
phaseolina	I-PATHOGEN
was	O
re	O
-	O
isolated	O
from	O
leaves	B-PLANT_PART
with	O
leaf	B-SYMPTOM
blight	I-SYMPTOM
symptoms	O
.	O

Macrophomina	O
is	O
typically	O
found	O
to	O
cause	O
root	B-PLANT_PART
and	O
lower	B-SYMPTOM
stem	I-SYMPTOM
rot	I-SYMPTOM
on	O
cassava	B-CROP
in	O
Africa	B-LOC
(	O
Msikita	O
et	O
al	O
.	O
,	O
1998	B-DATE
)	O
.	O
To	O
the	O
best	O
of	O
our	O
knowledge	O
,	O

this	O
is	O
the	O
first	O
report	O
of	O
M.	B-PATHOGEN
phaseolina	I-PATHOGEN
causing	O
leaf	B-DISEASE
blight	I-DISEASE
on	O
cassava	B-CROP
in	O
China	B-GPE
.	O

Our	O
finding	O
provides	O
a	O
foundation	O
to	O
management	O
of	O
this	O
disease	O
.	O
